The Mainprice Deposit
The Mainprice Deposit
14th century-19th century
E.7.1-F.2.12
Main
c. 5.85 cubic metres (76 boxes)
Chetham's Library
Taylor, Kirkman and Mainprice, solicitors
This large collection of deeds and papers mainly concerns land and property in Lancashire and Cheshire, but other counties also feature, including Essex, Hertfordshire and Middlesex. The collection also contains twelve documents relating to Chetham's Hospital's estate at Sutton on the Hill, Derbyshire, which was sold in 1919 to raise capital for the Hospital.
The collection consists of deeds and miscellaneous papers, with a large number of mortgages, wills, probates, leases and releases, conveyances, and bargains and sales.
There are no restrictions on access to this collection. Viewing is by prior appointment. Please contact archivist@chethams.org.uk.
Deposited by Taylor, Kirkman and Mainprice, solicitors, between October 1940 and [1946].
The collection has been divided into six sub-fonds:
Documents relating to Lancashire, Cheshire and other counties, 14th century-19th century
The Chetham/Clowes Deeds, 15th century-19th century
Documents relating to the Astley-Nicholson family of Dukinfield, co Ches, 1779-1913
Documents relating to the Gorton and Culceth families, 1640-1813
Documents relating to Lancashire and Cheshire, 1564-1809
Documents relating to counties other than Lancashire and Cheshire, 16th century-19th century
The legal firm of Taylor, Kirkman and Mainprice was founded in the late 19th century. It became the solicitors to the Feoffees of Chetham's Hospital and Library, and this connection led to the deposit of a large collection of deeds and papers in Chetham's Library during the 1940s. The firm continues to practice but has been incorporated into Butcher and Barlow solicitors. Its offices are located in Bramhall, Cheshire.
Land tenure -- England; Deeds; Estate management; Mortgages (documents); Wills; Solicitors; Astley, Francis Dukinfield. (1781-1825 ) Cheshire landowner and poet; Astley, Francis Dukinfield Palmer. (1825-1868 ); Chetham, James. (bapt. 1682 d. 1752 ) of Smedley; Taylor, Kirkman and Mainprice, solicitors -- Bramhall, England; Lancashire -- England; Cheshire -- England; Manchester -- England; Salford -- England; Broughton -- Lancashire -- England; Kersal -- Lancashire -- England; Taxal -- Cheshire -- England; Sedgley -- Staffordshire -- England; Dukinfield -- Cheshire -- England; Sutton on the Hill -- Derbyshire -- England; Gorton -- Lancashire -- England; Moston -- Lancashire -- England
- Documents relating to Lancashire, Cheshire and other counties, 14th century-19th century; GB/418/E/7/1-E/7/6; GB/418/Main/1; 318 files; Chetham's Library
  Miscellaneous collection of deeds deposited in Chetham's Library in October 1940 by F. H. Mainprice of Taylor, Kirkman and Mainprice, solicitors to the Feoffees of Chetham's Hospital and Library. Many of the deeds are concerned with the Manchester area, with Taxal in Cheshire, and there are some concerned with Sutton on the Hill, Derbyshire, one of the estates which provided Chetham's Hospital School with income.
  The deeds were not put in order when they arrived at the library, but were simply numbered and listed by C.T.E. Phillips, Chetham's Librarian, who provided an index of names. The collection is divided into two lots: Lot 1 reference E.7.1-E.7.4, total of 231 deeds; Lot 2 reference E.7.5-E.7.6, total of 87 deeds.
  The deeds were reboxed in January 1989. Phillips's order is as follows:
  E.7.1 Lot 1 nos. 1-60
  E.7.2 Lot 1 nos. 61-98
  E.7.3 Lot 1 nos. 99-160
  E.7.4 Lot 1 nos. 161-231
  E.7.5 Lot 2 nos. 1-52
  E.7.6 Lot 2 nos. 53-87
  The documents were rearranged on paper in a chronological order within an alphabetical order of places in 1989. Owing to Phillips's division of the collection into two lots, and the consequent duplication of the numbering sequence, it was necessary to prefix the lot number 2 to the reference given by Phillips.Thus (2) 81 is lot 2 number 81. Deeds belonging to lot 1 have no prefix.
  - Documents relating to Agecroft, co Lancs, 1785-1833; GB/418/E.7.1 & E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/1; 6 files; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of the tolls from Agecroft Turnpike Bar to Samuel Clowes, junior, 6 Jan 1785; GB/418/E.7.4 (218); GB/418/Main/1/1/1; Chetham's Library
    - Declaration of a trust advanced upon a mortgage from the tolls from the turnpike near Agecroft Bridge from Samuel Clowes, junior, to Charles and William Coke and others, 7 Jan 1785; GB/418/E.7.4 (219); GB/418/Main/1/1/2; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of £100 owing from Agecroft Toll Bar from Ralph Yates to Rev John Dauntesey, 10 Jan 1797; GB/418/E.7.4 (220); GB/418/Main/1/1/3; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of three undivided fourth parts of shares of £100 secured on the tolls of the Turnpike at Agecroft from James Hope, Thomas Hope and Ellis Hope, to Isaac Hope, 16 Nov 1811; GB/418/E.7.1 (8); GB/418/Main/1/1/4; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of an Assignment given by the Trustees of Agecroft Bridge Turnpike Road from William Harrison, Mark Nightingale and John Grantham to Richard Higginson, 7 Feb 1824; GB/418/E.7.4 (223); GB/418/Main/1/1/5; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls of the Agecroft district of turnpike roads to Mrs Maria Coppock for securing £160 and interest, later transferred from Maria Coppock to Charles Cooke of Salford, 24 Jun 1829 & 10 Aug 1833; GB/418/E.7.1 (12); GB/418/Main/1/1/6; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Barton, co Lancs, 1662-1837; GB/418/E/7/3 & E/7/4; GB/418/Main/1/2; 14 files; Chetham's Library
    - Grant of tithes etc in Barton from Francis Anderton of Lostock to William Shrigley of Barton, 1 Sep 1662; GB/418/E.7.4 (207); GB/418/Main/1/2/1; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Ralph Robinson of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 1 May 1821, 13 Apr 1821; GB/418/E.7.3 (126); GB/418/Main/1/2/2; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Ralph Robinson of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 1 May 1822, 10 Apr 1822; GB/418/E.7.3 (127); GB/418/Main/1/2/3; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Richard Roberts of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 1 May 1828, 17 Mar 1828; GB/418/E.7.3 (102); GB/418/Main/1/2/4; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Thomas Lowe of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 3 May 1829, 9 Mar 1829; GB/418/E.7.3 (103); GB/418/Main/1/2/5; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to William Longbotham of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 2 May 1830, 12 Apr 1830; GB/418/E.7.3 (104); GB/418/Main/1/2/6; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Jesup Halliwell, junior, of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 13 Feb 1831, 9 Feb 1831; GB/418/E.7.3 (105); GB/418/Main/1/2/7; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Richard Roberts, junior, of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 12 Jun 1832, 7 Jun 1832; GB/418/E.7.3 (106); GB/418/Main/1/2/8; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Robert Arrowsmith of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 12 Jun 1833, 6 Jun 1833; GB/418/E.7.3 (107); GB/418/Main/1/2/9; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Thomas Noble of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 12 Jun 1834, GB/418/E.7.3 (108); GB/418/Main/1/2/10; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to John Knowles, senior, of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 12 Jun 1835, 22 Apr 1835; GB/418/E.7.3 (109); GB/418/Main/1/2/11; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Jesup Halliwell, the younger, of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge tunpike and weighing machine for one year from 31 Dec 1835, 16 Dec 1835; GB/418/E.7.3 (110); GB/418/Main/1/2/12; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to George Lowe of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 31 Dec 1836, 19 Dec 1836; GB/418/E.7.3 (111); GB/418/Main/1/2/13; Chetham's Library
    - Lease to Richard Roberts of the tolls collected at Barton Bridge turnpike and weighing machine for one year from 31 Dec 1837, GB/418/E.7.4 (162); GB/418/Main/1/2/14; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Blackley, co Lancs, 1807; GB/418/E.7.4 (179); GB/418/Main/1/3; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Probate copy of the will and four codicils of Thomas Henshaw of Blackley, co Lancs, 14 Nov 1807; GB/418/E.7.4 (179); GB/418/Main/1/3/1; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Bristol, 1744; GB/418/E.7.1 (45); GB/418/Main/1/4; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - The will of Benjamin Johnson of St Thomas in the City of Bristol, 15 Oct 1744; GB/418/E.7.1 (45); GB/418/Main/1/4/1; Chetham's Library
      Probate attached dated 1 Oct 1750.
  - Document relating to Congleton, co Ches, 1811; GB/418/E.7.1 (23); GB/418/Main/1/5; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Borough of Congleton: Certificate of Freemanship of James Brierly, 13 Apr 1811; GB/418/E.7.1 (41); GB/418/Main/1/5/1; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Culcheth, co Ches, 1322-1834; GB/418/E.7.1 & E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/6; 5 files; Chetham's Library
    - Grant of four acres and a half of land in the Slacke, in the town of Culcheth, [1322]; GB/418/E.7.1 (45); GB/418/Main/1/6/1; Chetham's Library
      From Richard de Twisse to John de Shawe and Alice his wife
    - Grant from Gilbert de Culcheth to Richard de Margery, [1339]; GB/418/E.7.4 (202); GB/418/Main/1/6/2; Chetham's Library
      13 Edw III
    - Lease of land in Culcheth from William de Culcheth to William, son of Thomas of Wigan, 1342; GB/418/E.7.4 (203); GB/418/Main/1/6/3; Chetham's Library
    - Grant from the King (Henry IV) to Hammet Massy Esq of £10 per annum, 23 Sep [1400]; GB/418/E.7.4 (201); GB/418/Main/1/6/4; Chetham's Library
      2 Hen IV
    - Will and probate of Mr Gerrard Brown of Culcheth, 27 Jan 1834; GB/418/E.7.1 (59); GB/418/Main/1/6/5; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Eccleshall, co Staffs, 1771-1813; GB/418/E.7.1 & E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/7; 4 files; Chetham's Library
    - Manor of Eccleshall Court Leet and Court Baron: Surrender of the Hon John Campbell (Lord Viscount Glenorchy), 24 Apr 1771; GB/418/E.7.1 (17); GB/418/Main/1/7/1; Chetham's Library
    - Manor of Eccleshall Court Leet and Court Baron: Copies of the Surrender of Mr Pickering to Mr Turton and his Admittance thereon and Surrender to the uses of his Will and Admittance thereof, 18 Apr 1774; GB/418/E.7.1 (16); GB/418/Main/1/7/2; Chetham's Library
    - Manor of Eccleshall: Surrender and Admittance, John Turton to John Thorne, 9 Oct 1799; GB/418/E.7.4 (182); GB/418/Main/1/7/3; Chetham's Library
    - Manor of Eccleshall: Surrender and Admittance, John Thomas of Liverpool to Charles Rowland, 28 Apr 1813; GB/418/E.7.4 (181); GB/418/Main/1/7/4; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Eccleston, co Lancs, 1797 & 1813; GB/418/E.7.3 & E.7.1; GB/418/Main/1/8; 2 files; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of a messuage and tenement in Eccleston, for the residue of a term of 120 years from John Riddihough and others to Robert Leigh and James Birchall, 26 Feb 1813; GB/418/E.7.3 (120); GB/418/Main/1/8/1; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of an estate in Eccleston for three lives from Thomas Eccleston to Thomas Johnson, 20 Jul 1797; GB/418/E.7.1 (35); GB/418/Main/1/8/2; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Flixton, co Lancs, 1809; GB/418/E.7.4 (178); GB/418/Main/1/9; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Probate of the will of William Gerrard of Flixton, co Lancs, 29 Jul 1809; GB/418/E.7.4 (178); GB/418/Main/1/9/1; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Glazebrook, co Ches, [1383-?c 1390]; GB/418/E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/10; 3 files; Chetham's Library
    - Grant of the Manor of Rixton and one moiety of the Manor of Glasebroke from Richard le Massy of Rixton to Henry de Rixton, [1383]; GB/418/E.7.4 (205); GB/418/Main/1/10/1; Chetham's Library
      6 Ric II
    - Grant of property in Glasebroke from William, son of Mathilda de Glasebroke, to Alan de Rixton, nd [?1390]; GB/418/E.7.4 (204); GB/418/Main/1/10/2; Chetham's Library
    - Feoffment of premises in Glasebroke from Robert, son of Robert de Glasebroke to Alan, Lord of Rixton, nd [?14th century]; GB/418/E.7.4 (200); GB/418/Main/1/10/3; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Heaton Moor, co Lancs, 1767; GB/418/E.7.1 (39); GB/418/Main/1/11; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Lease from Samuel Egerton to James Green of 18 acres on Heaton Moor, 2 Feb 1767; GB/418/E.7.3 (133); GB/418/Main/1/11/1; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Heaton Norris, co Lancs, 1787 & 1779; GB/418/E.7.3 & E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/12; 2 files; Chetham's Library
    - Demise from Joseph Green to James Heap for securing £150 and interest, 3 Feb 1787; GB/418/E.7.3 (113); GB/418/Main/1/12/1; Chetham's Library
    - Will of James Green of Heaton Norris, 18 Jan 1779; GB/418/E.7.4 (192); GB/418/Main/1/12/2; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Hindley, co Lancs, 1654-1698; GB/418/E.7.1 (22-26 & 28); GB/418/Main/1/13; 7 files; Chetham's Library
    - Sale of land called the Great Hindley Fields from Abraham Langton and Philip Langton to Thomas Lythgoe etc, 26 Sep 1654; GB/418/E.7.1 (22); GB/418/Main/1/13/1; Chetham's Library
    - Grant and Release from Gilbert Lythgoe to James Smith of lands in Hindley, 23 & 24 Jul 1690; GB/418/E.7.1 (23); GB/418/Main/1/13/2; 2 deeds; Chetham's Library
    - Deed to declare the uses of a recovery of lands in Hindley from William Patten and Richard Langton to James Smith, 15 Jan 1690; GB/418/E.7.1 (24); GB/418/Main/1/13/3; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of recovery from William Patten and Richard Langton to James Smith, 20 Aug 1690; GB/418/E.7.1 (24*); GB/418/Main/1/13/4; Chetham's Library
    - Sale of lands in Hindley from James Smith to Elizabeth Mather, 30 Jan 1698; GB/418/E.7.1 (25); GB/418/Main/1/13/5; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of several closes of land in Hindley from James Smith to Elizabeth Mather, 30 & 31 Jan 1698; GB/418/E.7.1 (26); GB/418/Main/1/13/6; Chetham's Library
    - Grant of a road in Hindley from Edward Langton and James Cheetham to Elizabeth and Nicholas Mather, 2 Feb 1698; GB/418/E.7.1 (28); GB/418/Main/1/13/7; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Irlam, co Lancs, 1805-1836; GB/418/E.7.1 & E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/14; 12 files; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls from Gilda Bridge and Irlam turnpikes to William Craven, 10 Jan 1805; GB/418/E.7.4 (227); GB/418/Main/1/14/1; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of the toll from Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpikes to John Grundy, 10 Apr 1813; GB/418/E.7.4 (221); GB/418/Main/1/14/2; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of the tolls from Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpikes to John Farnworth, 10 Apr 1813; GB/418/E.7.4 (222); GB/418/Main/1/14/3; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls from Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpikes to John Grundy, 17 Jun 1816; GB/418/E.7.4 (214); GB/418/Main/1/14/4; Chetham's Library
    - Transfer and assignment of £300 owing on security of the tolls from Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpike from John Newton etc to Alice Nichols, 17 Jan 1820; GB/418/E.7.4 (230); GB/418/Main/1/14/5; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls from Irlam turnpike to John Cooke, 2 Nov 1821; GB/418/E.7.4 (211); GB/418/Main/1/14/6; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls from Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpikes to John Cooke, 7 Jun 1821; GB/418/E.7.4 (212); GB/418/Main/1/14/7; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls from Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpikes to John Greaves, 10 Oct 1822; GB/418/E.7.4 (213); GB/418/Main/1/14/8; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls from Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpikes to John Cooke, 11 Apr 1822; GB/418/E.7.4 (215); GB/418/Main/1/14/9; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls arising from the Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpike road to Samuel Walker Esq for securing £1500 and interest, 20 Oct 1828; GB/418/E.7.1 (19); GB/418/Main/1/14/10; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls of Gilda Brook and Irlam district of turnpike roads to Samuel Walker Esq for securing £2500 and interest, 24 Mar 1829; GB/418/E.7.1 (7); GB/418/Main/1/14/11; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of £300 owing on account of the tolls of the Gilda Brook and Irlam turnpikes from Alice Nichols to Samuel Walker, 23 Mar 1836; GB/418/E.7.4 (228); GB/418/Main/1/14/12; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Irlam O' Th' Height, co Lancs, 1829-1844; GB/418/E.7.1 & E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/15; 4 files; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls from Irlam o' th' Height turnpike to Samuel Walker of Pendleton, 1 Jul 1828; GB/418/E.7.4 (217); GB/418/Main/1/15/1; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of tolls in the Irlam o' th' Height of turnpikes to Margaret Hibbert, 10 Sep 1829; GB/418/E.7.4 (209); GB/418/Main/1/15/2; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls of Irlam o' th' Height district of turnpikes to Samuel Walker, 3 Aug 1829; GB/418/E.7.4 (210); GB/418/Main/1/15/3; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls of the Irlam o' th' Height district of turnpike roads to James Rothwell Barns Esq for securing £750 and interest, 26 Apr 1844; GB/418/E.7.1 (14); GB/418/Main/1/15/4; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Kearsley, co Lancs, 1742; GB/418/E.7.1 (31 & 37); GB/418/Main/1/16; 2 files; Chetham's Library
    - Grant of coal and canal in Kearsley between Peter Dorning and Jacob Fletcher, 26 Mar 1742; GB/418/E.7.1 (31); GB/418/Main/1/16/1; Chetham's Library
    - Bond for performance of covenants of Jacob Fletcher, 26 Mar 1742; GB/418/E.7.1 (37); GB/418/Main/1/16/2; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Liverpool, co Lancs, 1773 & 1835; GB/418/E.7.1 (58) & E.7.2 (66); GB/418/Main/1/17; 2 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance from Mrs Ann Dawson of Liverpool to her daughter Hannah Dawson of a share of the estate of Edward Goodall, 13 Jul 1773; GB/418/E.7.1 (58); GB/418/Main/1/17/1; Chetham's Library
      Also appointment of several parts of the late James Booth's estate
    - Settlement made previous to the marriage of Joseph Donnell of Liverpool and Ann Appleby of Birmingham, 3 Oct 1835; GB/418/E.7.2 (66); GB/418/Main/1/17/2; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Lostock, co Lancs, 1826; GB/418/E.7.2 (62); GB/418/Main/1/18; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Probate of the will, with codicil, of Thomas Chorlton of Lostock in the parish of Eccles, co Lancs, 21 Jan 1826; GB/418/E.7.2 (62); GB/418/Main/1/18/1; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Manchester, co Lancs, 1672-1880; GB/418/E.7.1-E.7.6; GB/418/Main/1/19; 58 files; Chetham's Library
    - Deed of Purchase from Stephen Radley, John Byrom, Ellis Hay and Margaret Radcliffe to William Hunter, 15 Jul 1672; GB/418/E.7.1 (48); GB/418/Main/1/19/1; Chetham's Library
      "at the Cross in Manchester"
    - Conveyance of houses, shops etc in or near the Market Stead or Market Cross in Manchester from William Hunter to John Sandiford, 31 Mar 1674; GB/418/E.7.1 (43); GB/418/Main/1/19/2; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of a lease of houses etc near Market Cross, Manchester from John Sandiford to Robert Diggles, 29 Mar 1674; GB/418/E.7.1 (46); GB/418/Main/1/19/3; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of property near the Golden Lion, Market Place, Manchester from John Sandiford of Manchester to John Oldfield, 25 Mar 1708; GB/418/E.7.4 (189); GB/418/Main/1/19/4; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for six months of properties in or near Milne Gate, Manchester from John Diggles to Jeremiah Aldred, John Andrews, Thomas and James Diggles, 28 Dec 1711; GB/418/E.7.1 (44); GB/418/Main/1/19/5; Chetham's Library
    - Settlement of John Diggles of houses etc in or near Milngate and on the East side of the Market Cross in Manchester, upon his marriage with Mary Mort, 29 Dec 1711; GB/418/E.7.3 (139); GB/418/Main/1/19/6; Chetham's Library
    - Final Concord concerning seven messuages and five gardens etc in Manchester, 28 Mar 1713; GB/418/E.7.4 (199 a and b); GB/418/Main/1/19/7; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      Between Jeremiah Alvered, John Andrews, Thomas and James Diggles, plaintiffs, and John Diggles and Ann his wife, defendants. (With counterpart)
    - Agreement regarding a brick wall about a garden in Manchester between Richard Moss to Robert Diggles, 27 Oct 1713; GB/418/E.7.1 (47); GB/418/Main/1/19/8; Chetham's Library
    - Plan and details of an estate in Market Place, Manchester belonging to Samuel Shore of Sheffield, 23 Sep 1737; GB/418/E.7.1 (1); GB/418/Main/1/19/9; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of several messuages etc near the Market Cross, Manchester, from Samuel Shaw to Richard Booth, 20 Apr 1738; GB/418/E.7.3 (144); GB/418/Main/1/19/10; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for 6 months of property near Market Cross, Manchester, from Samuel Shaw to Richard Booth, 19 Apr 1738; GB/418/E.7.3 (145); GB/418/Main/1/19/11; Chetham's Library
    - Marriage Agreement between Samuel Barton and Elizabeth Harrison, 23 Aug 1739; GB/418/E.7.1 (49); GB/418/Main/1/19/12; Chetham's Library
    - Release of messuages etc in Manchester from Edward and James Goodall to William Dawson and others, 29 Jun 1750; GB/418/E.7.3 (116); GB/418/Main/1/19/13; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for a year of property in Manchester from Edward and James Goodall to William Dawson and James Grantham, 28 Jun 1750; GB/418/E.7.4 (183); GB/418/Main/1/19/14; Chetham's Library
    - Settlement of lands in Manchester from Richard Booth to Benjamin Dawson, 13 Jun 1751; GB/418/E.7.3 (134); GB/418/Main/1/19/15; Chetham's Library
    - Will of Richard Booth of Manchester, 16 Oct 1751; GB/418/E.7.4 (193); GB/418/Main/1/19/16; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for a year from Mrs Sarah Marsh to Dudley Fereday, 29 Dec 1822; GB/418/E.7.3 (140); GB/418/Main/1/19/17; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of Term from Mrs Dorothy Phillips of Wakefield etc to John Eagle in trust for Abraham Balme, 29 Jul 1752; GB/418/E.7.4 (164); GB/418/Main/1/19/18; Chetham's Library
    - One part of the Deed of Division or Partition of lands in Manchester between James Booth and Hannah Booth, devised to them by their father's will, 8 Aug 1758; GB/418/E.7.3 (135); GB/418/Main/1/19/19; Chetham's Library
    - Indenture of sale of a pew or seat on the North side of the middle aisle of St Mary's Church, Manchester, 20 Dec 1759; GB/418/E.7.1 (5); GB/418/Main/1/19/20; Chetham's Library
      Between the Warden and Fellows of the College of Christ in Manchester and Josiah Nichols.
    - Indenture of sale of a pew or seat in St Mary's Church, 21 Dec 1759; GB/418/E.7.1 (6); GB/418/Main/1/19/21; Chetham's Library
      Between the Warden and Fellows of the College of Christ in Manchester, William Starkey and Thomas Chadwick of the second part, and Josiah Nichols of the third part.
    - Memorandum of Agreement between Ann Dawson of Liverpool and Hannah Dawson, and Joseph Berry of Manchester, 24 Jun 1773; GB/418/E.7.4 (194); GB/418/Main/1/19/22; Chetham's Library
    - Memorandum of Agreement concerning a house near Paradize (Paradise) Court, Manchester, 24 Jun 1773; GB/418/E.7.4 (196); GB/418/Main/1/19/23; Chetham's Library
      Between Ann Dawson of Liverpool and Hannah Dawson, and John Sanderson of Manchester
    - Lease for possession of a third part of some lands in Manchester between Ann Dawson of Liverpool and Peter Lowe of Manchester, 12 Jul 1773; GB/418/E.7.1 (57); GB/418/Main/1/19/24; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of a term of one thousand years to attend the inheritance of premises conveyed to Hannah Dawson, 17 Jul 1778; GB/418/E.7.1 (38); GB/418/Main/1/19/25; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Cooper to Hannah Lowe.